DANILA SOTNIK

+79032805720 | work.sotnik@gmail.com | Vancouver, British Columbia

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Authorized to work in Canada.

Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience in different types of web applications from financial data-driven to maps based on GIS data, leading projects through the full development life cycle using Agile methodologies. Highly developed soft skills allow me to successfully build communication with teams and indirect departments. Inspired by web and C++ development, courses and technical literature with daily self-education. Major achievement: I developed GIS solution, including geo-feature constructor on UI and "level of details" at map with 200k+ features on small extent. Customer was interested in my developments and added them into contract budget.

Experience

ITARGO

Software Engineer - Front-End | 03/2019 - Present

- Developed and maintained JavaScript (ES6) code for complex and significant financial applications used by 34 community organizations to manage construction projects on different devices (desktops, tablets, mobiles).
- Updated project from Angular 1 to Vue 2 with a 24% performance increase according to Lighthouse analysis.
- Integrated data virtualization tools and reduced data processing time by ~50%, through improved coding practices and algorithm optimization.
- Mentored a team of junior developers, providing code reviews and technical guidance; trained newcomers and expanded their productivity by 35% according to KPI calculations.
- Provided consulting and System Design analysis for the frontend part of 3 other internal projects, accelerating the time to reach prototype deployment milestones by ~25%.
- Collaborated with the design team to create pixel-perfect layouts, improving customer satisfaction by 2 times.
- Modified web application under the Web Accessibility Initiative (WAI), increasing accessibility by 18%.

Renault

Purchasing Department Specialist | 10/2016 - 02/2019

- Managed electrical automotive parts panel (Multimedia, lighting, HVAC) with 20+ suppliers, launched Renault "Dakar".
- Built operational communication between the company engineering department and suppliers' engineers, reducing time for technical product validation by 15% on average.
- Analyzed the market and negotiated with suppliers to provide 8% saving from electrical parts turnover in the 2018 year.
- Contracted special conditions for spare parts production and logistics, growing the level of availability by 20% and the level of on-time shipments by 60%.

Bosch

Quality Management Intern | 04/2016 - 06/2016

- Organized internal conference about industrial safety under ISO 9001, ISO 14001, and OHSAS 18001 with ~95% department attendance.
- Created and validated document with the rules for proper movement through production sites, within 3 weeks.

Skills

JavaScript, TypeScript, Vue, React, C++, GIS, ArcGIS, OpenLayers, React Native, Node.js, HTML, CSS, Git, AWS, Docker

Education

RSUH

Bachelor's degree | 08/2017

Languages

English, Russian